Welcome back to Jupyter Lab and welcome to Day Five's Lab.
주피터 연구소에 잘 오셨습니다 파이브의 연구실에도요
And this is going to be lots of creativity and hopefully lots of entertainment.
창의력이 많이 발휘될 거고 오락성도 많으면 좋겠어요
So to start with I have copied the day four Jupyter Lab.
우선 4일째의 주피터 연구소를 모사했어요
And I've duplicated that.
그걸 복사했어요
And then I've extended it.
그리고 확장했어요
So everything above where I am now is just a repeat of day four.
지금 여기 위로는 나흘째의 반복이에요
Creates the AI assistant for our airline called flight flight AI, something like that, and arms it
우리 항공사의 AI 보조를 만들었어요 비행기 AI라고 불렀죠 그리고 비행기 표 가격을 알아낼
with a tool to be able to get ticket prices.
도구를 장착했어요
All of that is already there and I've executed it ready for our showtime today.
모든 게 이미 갖춰져 있고 오늘 공연에 맞게 완성했어요
We're going to go multi-modal.
다중 모듈로 갈 거예요
We're going to use Dall-E three, which is the image generation model that sits behind GPT four.
달레3을 사용할 건데요 GPT 4 뒤에 있는 이미지 생성 모델이에요
We're going to use it to make some images.
이미지를 만드는 데 사용할 거예요
And let's start by putting it into a function called artist.
아티스트라는 함수에 넣는 것으로 시작하죠
Before that, there are two, uh, service announcements I should make.
그 전에 두 가지 서비스 공지를 해야 해요
Uh, first of all, I should point out that the price associated with generating an image is not tiny.
먼저 이미지 생성에 드는 비용은 아주 적지 않아요
Everything that we've done so far, I hope, has had a de minimis price in the fractions of a cent.
지금까지 한 모든 게 1센트 미만이라도 적게 들었으면 좋겠어요
Unless you've been generating tons of lengthy brochures, you have not racked up a significant bill
당신이 엄청나게 긴 책자를 만든 게 아니라면 지금까지 이 과정을 진행했다고 해서
from running this course so far.
큰돈을 번 건 아니에요
But now we are doing something that's slightly more on the radar.
하지만 지금은 좀 더 눈에 띄는 일을 하고 있어요
Each image that we generate will cost $0.04.
우리가 생성하는 이미지마다 0달러가 들어요 4시요
Now, I put it to you that when you see these images, you will agree that they are well worth $0.04
이 사진들을 보시면 0달러의 가치가 있다는 걸 아실 거예요 Put 각각 04달러요
And they are super creative and high value.
아주 창의적이고 가치도 높아요
And I love them.
정말 좋아요
So I think it is money well spent.
돈을 잘 쓴 것 같아요
But I do want to inform you of that so that you can decide whether you want to spend your $0.04 each
하지만 그걸 알려드리고 싶어요 0달러를 쓸지 말지 결정하시라고요 한 번에 04개요
Uh, the other thing to mention is that there is a little bit of, uh, um, uh, there's there's a
언급하고 싶은 다른 것은 약간 그러니까 이미지 생성이나 음향
there's a point about whether or not one should use the term LM when referring to image generation and
생성 같은 것을 말할 때 LM이라는 용어를 써야 할지에 대한 논점이 있어요
audio generation and the like.
비트
Text to audio.
문자로 오디오를 연결해요
Because of course, these are not large language models sitting behind the scenes.
물론 이건 무대 뒤에 있는 대형 언어 모델이 아니니까요
Now, what tends to happen these days is that people use LM as a bit of a general term for the models
요즘 사람들은 LM을 일반 용어로 사용합니다 인공지능 시스템 뒤에 있는
that sit behind gen AI systems.
모델을 일컫는 비트죠
So actually, in practice, I think this very much is part of the skill set and toolkit of an LM engineer.
실제로 LM 엔지니어가 갖춰야 할 기술과 도구라고 생각해요
But I should mention that, of course, strictly speaking, these aren't language models.
하지만 엄밀히 말하면 이건 언어 모델이 아니에요
These are image models and audio models that we'll be playing with right now as we add them to our agent
이것들은 이미지 모델과 오디오 모델입니다 에이전트 프레임워크에 추가할 때 실행할
framework.
수 있죠
Anyways, with that preamble, let's get on with it.
어쨌든 서문은 됐고, 이제 시작하죠. Get it.
So we start by importing some useful image libraries.
유용한 이미지 라이브러리 가져오기로 시작하죠
Well, the first one isn't.
첫 번째는 아니에요
First two aren't image libraries, but some, some, uh, utilities.
처음 두 개는 이미지 라이브러리가 아니라 일부 유틸리티예요
And then the Python image library is going to be very useful for us, a very handy common library.
파이썬 이미지 라이브러리는 아주 유용합니다 아주 편리한 공통 라이브러리예요
Uh, so the next thing we do is we're going to write a function called artist and artist calls OpenAI
다음으로 할 일은 아티스트라는 함수를 작성하는 겁니다 아티스트는 OpenAI.Nagees.Nageate를
dot images dot generate.
호출하죠
So it's a very consistent style that you're used to OpenAI images generate.
OpenAI 이미지 생성에 사용되는 스타일이 아주 일관적이죠
We pass in the name of a model.
모델 이름을 통과해요
In this case, the model is Dall-E three.
이 경우에는 모델이 달어리 쓰리예요
You could also try Dall-E two, its predecessor.
그 전신인 달이 2호도 한번 드셔 보세요
The images are less awesome.
이미지는 less예요
It's a bit cheaper.
비트가 좀 더 저렴해요
I seem to remember it's about $0.02 rather than $0.04, so it's not massively cheaper and in my opinion
0달러 정도였던 것 같아요 0달러가 아니라 02달러요 0달러면 많이 싼 편은 아닌데 0달러나
well worth the extra $0.02.
더 쓴 보람이 있네요 2번요
Stick with Dall-E three.
달리 쓰리 주세요
We give it a prompt and this isn't now a clever list of dictionaries.
즉각적으로 알려주면 이건 현명한 사전 목록이 아니죠
It's just text.
그냥 문자예요
And in this case, the prompt I'm suggesting here is, we say, an image representing a vacation in
이 경우에는 제가 제안하는 건 도시에서의 휴가를 상징하는 이미지예요
city, showing tourist spots and everything unique about city in a vibrant pop art style.
관광지와 도시의 모든 특징을 생동감 넘치는 팝아트 스타일로 표현하는 거죠
We give it a size that is the smallest size.
가장 작은 크기로 정해요
Dall-E three will do, Dall-E two will go much smaller.
달이 3개면 충분하고 달이 2개면 훨씬 작아요
Um and Dall-E three also does two larger sizes in a portrait and landscape format.
돌레 3도 초상과 가로 형식으로 큰 사이즈를 두 개 만들 수 있어요
Just google it if you'd like to know those dimensions.
크기가 궁금하면 구글에서 검색하세요
If you'd like to try those images.
이 이미지들을 시도해 보세요
We just want one image back.
이미지만 있으면 돼요
We say we want this format.
이 포맷을 원한다고 하죠
Back comes something in the, uh, this um, uh, base64 encoded format.
백은 베이스64 암호 형식으로 되어 있어요
We then decode that into bytes, and then we then create a bytes IO object on those bytes, which we
바이트 단위로 디코딩하고 그 바이트 단위로 바이트 IO 객체를 생성합니다
can then pass in to the image dot open function, and that will return an image for us.
그리고 나서 이미지.오픈 함수로 이동합니다 이미지를 반환해 주죠
Let's execute that.
실행해보죠
And now let's give it a try.
이제 한번 해 보죠
So I'm going to say image equals artist.
이미지 = 아티스트라고 하죠
And what shall we say New York City.
뭐라고 해야 할까요? 뉴욕시
And then display image is the Jupiter way of then getting that to show.
이미지를 디스플레이하는 건 그걸 보여주는 주피터 방식이죠
Let's run that or you're seeing one I ran already there.
실행해보죠, 아니면 이미 실행한 게 보이나요
Sorry it's not that quick, but look how amazing that is.
시간이 좀 걸리지만 정말 놀랍죠?
Uh, you're already getting.
이미 먹고 있잖아요
I'm spoiling you by showing you one right away.
바로 보여 드려서 버릇 나빠지게 해 드렸어요
This is what it looks like.
이렇게 생겼어요
It's generating a second one above you get to see the Statue of Liberty, a few different Empire State
두 번째 이미지를 위에 만들 거예요 자유의 여신상과 엠파이어
buildings, some planes in the sky, and then a sort of image to Times Square with lots of signs and
스테이트 빌딩 몇 개와 비행기들이 보이고 타임스 스퀘어 이미지와 많은 간판과 뉴욕 이미지가
with New York, spelled out their taxi.
택시를 나타내죠
Look at that.
보세요
A yellow New York taxi.
노란 뉴욕 택시요
And Coca-Cola.
코카콜라도요
And a hot dog.
핫도그도 있어요
A very New York iconic thing.
뉴욕의 상징이죠
Fantastic.
환상적이에요
Meanwhile, it's built another image for us here.
한편, 다른 이미지를 구축했어요
And.
그리고요
Wow, look at this one.
이것 좀 봐요
It's different.
달라요
It's great.
좋아요
It's got a big jet over here.
여기에 큰 제트기가 있어요
It's got the Empire State Building, of course, multiple Empire State buildings, Statue of Liberty's.
엠파이어 스테이트 빌딩도 있고 여러 채와 자유의 여신상도 있어요
And it's got again the sort of thriving shops and taxi in the foreground like that, an iconic New York
앞에는 번화한 상점들과 택시가 보이고 뉴욕의 상징적인 택시와 핫도그가
taxi and a hot dog again.
다시 등장하죠
Uh, so the thing to mention is that these images, they're so creative and they're so different, we've
이 사진들을 보면 정말 창의적이고 색다르다는 걸 알 수 있어요
got two now that we can see the one I did a moment ago and this one here, uh, and you can see how
두 장이 있는데 조금 전에 찍은 사진과 여기 있는 사진을 보면 얼마나
great they look.
멋진지 알 수 있죠
All right.
좋아요
Well, I hope that you were entertained by that.
재미있게 보셨길 바라요
And by all means, can I suggest spend some $0.04, generate a few images for yourself.
0달러 정도 쓰는 게 어때요? 04, 이미지 몇 개 만들어 보세요
They're great.
멋져요
All right, let's add one more function.
함수를 하나 더 추가할게요
We're going to make a function that uses OpenAI's speech to generate some audio.
OpenAI의 음성을 이용해 오디오를 생성하는 함수를 만들 거예요
So we're going to use a couple of utility stuff here with a library called Pi Dub.
파이덥이라는 라이브러리를 가진 몇 가지 유틸리티들을 이용할 거예요
That's very useful.
아주 유용하죠
We're going to write a function called talker.
토커라는 함수를 쓸 거예요
And talker is going to call OpenAI dot audio dot speech dot create.
토커는 OpenAI. audio.speaks.Crate라고 부를 거예요
So if we look back up the image generation was OpenAI images generate.
이미지 생성은 OpenAI 이미지가 생성된 것인데요
And for audio it's a case of uh OpenAI audio dot speech dot create.
오디오는 OpenAI audio.speaks.Create가 있네요
We pass in a model.
모형을 통과시키죠
Um, and this is the model we're using, TTS one TTS stands for text to speech and is, uh, the, the
이게 우리가 쓰는 모델이에요 TTS는 텍스트에서 음성으로 전환하는 모델이죠
this kind of model that we're going for, we supply a voice.
우리가 쓰는 모델은 목소리를 제공해요
In this case we're going to try the voice.
이번에는 목소리를 시험해 보죠
Onyx.
오닉스요
There's something like eight different voices to try again.
8개의 다른 목소리를 다시 녹음해야 했어요
You can you can Google to see what they are.
구글로 검색하면 다 나와요
And we pass in the thing that this function was called.
이 함수라고 불리는 것을 전달하죠
With what comes back, we again create a bytes IO object to represent those bytes.
결과를 보면 바이트당 IO 객체를 생성해 그 바이트를 나타내죠
And then we use this to this audio segment, uh creating it from a file and the audio stream and get
그리고 이걸 이 오디오 세그먼트에 사용합니다 파일과 오디오 스트림에서 생성해 해당 오디오를 재생하도록
it to play that audio.
get 하죠
So let's create that function and then let's say talker.
함수를 만들고 토크커라고 하죠
Well hi there.
안녕하세요
There we go.
됐어요
As simple as that.
아주 간단해요
Uh, let's see how another voice sounds.
다른 목소리는 어떤지 들어보죠
Let's see how alloy sounds.
합금 소리를 들어보죠
Let's put alloy in there.
합금을 넣죠 Put
Well hi there.
안녕하세요
And that was alloy.
합금으로 만든 거예요
I think we'll stick with onyx.
그냥 오닉스라고 하죠
But you can try either.
하지만 둘 다 가능해요
And you can also put in some more there that you can experiment with and pick your favorite.
그리고 여기에 더 넣어서 실험해보고 마음에 드는 걸 고르세요. Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it it up Put it up Put it up Put it Put it
All right.
좋아요
Well that's what we'll go with.
그렇게 하죠
Uh and now let's talk about the agent framework.
이제 에이전트 프레임워크에 대해 얘기해보죠
I think we will break for the next video.
다음 영상은 잠시 쉬죠
And that's where we'll take on our full agent framework.
거기서 에이전트 프레임워크를 다룰 거예요
See you then.
그때 봐요